Gowrishankar S

+919496115954 | gowrishankars02699@gmail.com | Thiruvananthapuram, Kerala

Summary

An adaptable student with knowledge of account development, brand management and client relations. Frequently praised for teamwork by my peers. Recent graduate equipped with a Three-year diploma in Mechanical Engineering with a concentration in Automobile Systems eager to join a reputable organization to begin a fulfilling, lifelong career with the added bonus of being a talented, sales-driven, recognized expert in the fields of direct sales and partner channel sales management. Equipped with 3+ years of experience in the areas of sales, marketing, business operations and development.

Education

MGM Polytechnic College | Thiruvananthapuram, Kerala Higher National Diploma in Mechanical Engineering | 04/2020

- · Awarded First division.
- Elected Captain of Polyhackathon in 2020
- Completed a Two-stroke Scrambler Bike as a Final year project.

Shantiniketan School | Thiruvananthapuram, Kerala All India Senior School Certificate Examination | 05/2017

Experience

Aanjaneyaa Musicals | Thiruvananthapuram , Kerala Sales Manager | 02/2020 - 02/2021

- Confer with potential customers regarding equipment needs and advise customers on types of equipment to purchase.
- Direct foreign sales and service outlets of the organization.
- Advise dealers and distributors on policies and operating procedures to ensure functional effectiveness of business.
- Monitor customer preferences to determine the focus of sales efforts.
- Direct, coordinate, and review activities in sales and service accounting and record keeping, and in receiving and shipping operations.
- Resolve customer complaints regarding sales and service.

SoLo

Business Owner | 02/2018 - Present

- Negotiate prices, discount terms and transportation arrangements for merchandise.
- Confer with sales and purchasing personnel to obtain information about customer needs and preferences.
- Examine, select, order, and purchase at the most favorable price merchandise consistent with quality, quantity, specification requirements and other factors.
- · Inspect merchandise or products to determine value or yield.
- · Perform buying duties when necessary.
- Contact suppliers in order to schedule or expedite deliveries and to resolve shortages, missed or late deliveries, and other problems.

Respond to customer and supplier inquiries about order status, changes, or cancellations.

Resolve customer complaints regarding sales and service.

Government polytechnic college, Attingal | Thiruvananthapuram, Kerala Apprentice Trainee | 03/2021 - 04/2022

- Evaluate and grade students' class work
- Supervise students' laboratory work.
- Conduct classes, workshops, and demonstrations to teach principles, techniques, or methods in subjects related to engineering.
- Confer with other staff members to plan and schedule lessons that promote learning, following approved curricula.
- Supervise and monitor students' use of tools and equipment.
- Administer oral, written, or performance tests to measure progress and evaluate training effectiveness.
- Acquire, maintain, and repair laboratory equipment and tools.

Aanjaneyaa Musicals | Thiruvananthapuram, Kerala Sales Management Trainee | 06/2017 - 02/2020

- Confer with potential customers regarding equipment needs and advise customers on types of equipment to purchase.
- Direct foreign sales and service outlets of the organization.
- Advise dealers and distributors on policies and operating procedures to ensure functional effectiveness of business.
- Monitor customer preferences to determine the focus of sales efforts.
- Direct, coordinate, and review activities in sales and service accounting and record keeping, and in receiving and shipping operations.
- Resolve customer complaints regarding sales and service.

Kerala State Road Transport Corporation | Thiruvananthapuram, Kerala Mechanical Engineer Intern | 06/2019 - 07/2019

- Apply engineering principles or practices to emerging fields, such as robotics, waste management, or biomedical engineering.
- Study industrial processes to determine where and how the application of equipment can be made.
- Design test control apparatus or equipment
- Establish or coordinate the maintenance or safety procedures, service schedule, or supply of materials required to maintain machines or equipment in the prescribed condition for testing products.

Skills

- · Networking Events
- Sales Records Management
- Budgeting and Expenditures
- Strategic Partnership
- Customer Service and Assistance
- Microsoft Office
- · Supervising Classroom Activities
- Experience with Diverse Student Populations
- Organizational and Planning Skills
- Technical Knowledge
- · Engineer Graphics
- Auto CAD
- · Advanced Machinery
- Automobile
- Piping

Certificates

- · Digital Marketing, Google April 2022
- Project Management, Google May 2022
- · Conducted a seminar on Hydrogen Fuel Cell

Co-Curricular Activities

- I have done volunteer work for NGOs like Art of giving and the Under 25 summit
- · I have also volunteered as a Kerala floods relief worker

Language

- English Advanced (C1)
- · Malayalam Native
- · Hindi Intermediate
- Tamil Intermediate
- · Japanese Beginner